

+64 21 1204611 macteariki@gmail.com macteariki.com

BIO

Mac Teariki is a web designer and developer based in Auckland, New Zealand.

His life has been a journey from visual communication, to programming, to interaction design and direction – in New Zealand, Japan, Germany and Italy.

This wide experience allows his to see the possibilities, know the obstacles, and to find what's original and practical.

EDUCATION

Graduate Diploma in Creative Technologies

Media Design School, Auckland

Feb 2015 - Dec 2015

Bachelor of Fine Arts

ELAM School of Fine Arts, University of Auckland

2009 - 2012

SKILLS

Core

Design, Development, UI/UX, Data visualisation

Coding

HTML

Javascript (ES6, React, D3)

CSS (& SASS)

Versioning (Git)

Gulp

<u>Software</u>

Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere, Sketch

EXPERIENCE

News Developer | NZ Herald, NZME

Feb 2016 - present

Currently working in editorial with the data/investigations team. I have produced data visualisations and interactives for Insights. Involved in a number of Herald campaigns and have collaborated with jounalists, videographers and photographers to create unique digital presentations for nzherald.co.nz.

Campaigns:

Rugby and the dementia dilemma

Olympics 2016

Under The Bridge

Break The Silence

The Great Escape

Web Designer | Napkin

Dec 2015 - Mar 2017

Responsible for the visual design and UI for trynapkin.co.nz - an online startup that provides a platform for finding, booking, and enjoying dining experiences prepared by private chefs.

Also designed the Napkin logo, built HTML email templates and created visuals for social media.

Online Content Administrator | NZ Herald, NZME

May 2014 – Jan 2016

Responsible for formatting and uploading content from the print edition to the Herald Online and regional websites. Assisted the Duty Editor with producing live news articles and ensuring content is published with accuracy and efficiency.